Shelenkov Anton Mikhailovich

Java developer

Moscow, Russia +7-926-534-26-61 anshelen@yandex.ru https://github.com/Anshelen

https://shelenkov.site/



Summary:

Java backend developer with 2.5 years of experience in developing and supporting services using Spring stack. Knowledgeable in microservice architecture and design patterns. Able to work with public blockchains Bitcoin and Ethereum, write smart contracts in Solidity language.

Have good verbal and written English skills at upper-intermediate level (have FCE certificate). Interested in DevOps technologies, wrote a series of articles about developing, deploying and operating of microservices application (https://habr.com/ru/post/487922/).

Skills:

- Confident knowledge of Java SE 8 11, Collections Framework, Concurrency
- Knowledge of algorithms and data structures, design patterns and basis of web-security
- Understand microservice architecture, develop web services (REST, Thrift) with asynchronous interaction via Apache Kafka and monitor them using ELK
- Experience with Spring Framework (Core, Boot, MVC, Data JPA, Security, OAuth2)
- Work with databases PostgreSQL, ClickHouse, Aerospike
- Confident knowledge of Hibernate, MyBatis, Flyway, Liquibase
- Test-driven development (TDD) using JUnit, Mockito
- Experience in web technologies JavaScript, ¡Query, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap 4
- Experience in using view generation technologies: Thymeleaf, Apache Wicket, Zk Framework
- Build projects with Maven and create Docker images
- Knowledge of Kubernetes container orchestration system and Helm package manager
- Build CI/CD pipeline for Kubernetes cluster with Jenkins
- Manage tasks with Jira, develop software on Agile (Kanban) methodology and make code reviews
- Work with Git
- Understanding of Bitcoin and Ethereum blockchains, smart-contracts development in Solidity language, experience in using Web3j and bitcoinj libraries

Experience:

Java developer in «Aximetria» (September 2019 – October 2020) – 1 year 1 month. Service for investing in cryptocurrencies (https://www.aximetria.com/). Some of tasks I have completed:

- Created anti-fraud algorithm for comparing user's full name with cardholder's data, considering transliteration, compound names, typos, abbreviations, etc.
- Designed subsidize transactions system that allowed users to transfer stablecoins without blockchain commissions
- Integrated with external video verification service and improved user identity system

Java developer at «IQManager» (October 2018 – July 2019) – 10 months. I worked unofficially part-time, combining with study in university. I supported and improved the site for organizing events (https://igmanager.org/). Some tasks:

- Integration with Sberbank acquiring system, implemented partial payments and automatic refunds
- I profiled admin panel and eliminated performance bottlenecks. It reduced the loading time of some pages by an order of magnitude
- Added and customized Google Maps to improve the user experience in interacting with the delivery system

Intern programmer at «Simplex Software» (November 2017 – September 2018) – 9 months. Software development company (https://www.simplex-software.ru/). I worked part-time, combining with study in university. Some of projects I took part in:

- Multithreaded parser of administrative cases card-file arbitr.ru
- PajCoin Ethereum-based token with smart contract acting as an exchange
- Discussion forum Talksift (http://talksift.ru/)

Education:

Bauman Moscow State University. Master degree in "Air conditioning systems" (2013 - 2019)

Additional education:

- «Algorithms: theory and practice. Methods» course certificate https://stepik.org/cert/187216
- «Algorithms: theory and practice. Data structures» course certificate https://stepik.org/cert/194175
- «Security analysis of web projects» course certificate https://stepik.org/cert/349423